Becher & Eitel business records
Connecticut Historical Society
Becher & Eitel business records
1895-1995
Connecticut Historical Society, Hartford, Connecticut
Becher & Eitel Bookbinders
2 linear feet (16 volumes, 46 items)
Historical Sketch
German born Fred Otto Becher (1873-1962) provided bookbinding services in Hartford, Connecticut before taking on a partner, another German by the name of Emil Eitel (b. ca. 1858). The firm, Becher & Eitel, was noted for the high quality of their work. In 1951 Becher appeared in an advertisement of the Smyth Manufacturing Company of Bloomfield. Becher was still using a Smyth book sewing machine that dated to 1891, the oldest continuously used machine the company could locate.
In the 1960s, President Robert Thorsell and Vice President Kathy Murawski took over operation of the company.
Scope and Content
Order books, sales records, payroll, scrapbook, correspondence, invoices, advertisements, and photographs of a Hartford, Connecticut bookbindery, founded by Fred Otto Becher. Later partner was Emil Eitel.
Access Restrictions
There are no restrictions on access to the collection.
Accruals
The collection is closed.
Subject Headings
Personal Names
Becher, Fred Otto.; Eitel, Emil, b. ca. 1858.
Subjects
Bookbinders -- Connecticut -- Hartford.
Contents:
- I. Records
  - Ledger, 1901-1906 (Volume 1)
  - Order book, 1901-1903 (Volume 2)
  - Sales record, 1928-1931 (Volume 3)
  - Sales record, 1931-1933 (Volume 4)
  - Sales record, 1933-1936 (Volume 5)
  - Sales record, 1937-1942 (Volume 6)
  - Order book, 1936-1939 (Volume 7)
  - Order book, 1939-1944 (Volume 8)
  - Order book, 1944-1949 (Volume 9)
  - Sales record, 1961-1965 (Volume 10)
  - Sales record, 1966-1970 (Volume 11)
  - Sales record, 1971-1975 (Volume 12)
  - Sales record, 1975-1979 (Volume 13)
  - Sales record, 1979-1981 (Volume 14)
  - Scrapbook, 1895-1971 (Volume 15)
  - Payroll, 1963 (Volume 16)
  - Correspondence (mostly thank you notes), 1990-1995 (Envelope 1, Folder 1)
  - Invoices, 1992-1995 (Envelope 1, Folder 2)
  - Advertisement, clippings, 1982, 1991-1994 (Envelope 1, Folder 3)
  - Photographs (of staff and their products), 1991, undated (Envelope 1, Folder 4)